Felix Sylvest Olesen

+852 63980687| felixolesen@gmail.com | Tooting, London, SW17 9TW
Github | LinkedIn | Itch.io

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A dedicated and excited Computer Science graduate with industrial experience creating and working on web-tools for testing and education. I am a passionate student of cutting-edge Web Development techniques and patterns. Along with participating in Hackathons I love to make and test video games in my free time.

SKILLS

Python, C#, Java, JavaScript, PHP, Full-Stack Web Development, Svelte, VueJS, Tailwind CSS, SQL, JQuery, Ruby on Rails, Trilingual Communicator (English, Danish, Spanish)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer, ICHK

December 2023 - February 2024

- ∉ Refactored custom alert PHP code in Gibbon resulting in a more object-oriented codebase.
- ∉ Re-designed the library catalogue feature to have Netflix-like rails UI and bookshelf-style backend using Tailwind CSS and SQL, making the catalogue more engaging for students.
- ✓ Communicated with students and teachers directly to create a clear and meaningful scope for the library catalogue feature and house points module in Gibbon.

Associate Test Engineer, Sky

June 2021 - July 2022

- ∉ Developed a replacement test tool using VueJS and Flask to send video-on-demand assets to test machines through the Sky backend, ensuring continued VOD test coverage.
- ∉ Automated my test cases using an in-house Python testing framework, enabling faster test coverage and improved time management.

EDUCATION

BSc (Hons) with Sandwich Year, Computer Science

July 2023

University of Surrey Grade Average: 79.6% University Project: Spotify Run Planner

January 2021 - June 2021

Grade: 69%

- Implemented and hosted a run planner app that linked up with the Spotify API to generate playlists for you depending on the desired pace, distance, and heartrate at which the user wants to run.
- Worked in a team as the project manager to undergo a full Agile project development lifecycle, assigning work towards documenting, programming, testing the whole process.
- Conducted full-stack web development with Ruby on Rails and SQL to create featurecomplete website thanks to the hard work and organizational skills conducted in our biweekly scrum meetings.

University Project: Game Discussion Forum September 2020 – December 2021

Grade: 86%

- ∉ Conducted thorough test coverage of all information displayed on each page of the website, to ensure automated and full test coverage.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

GameJam Participant, Aquetect

March 2024 - Present

- Participated in the PixelJam 2024 GameJam to create a game under the theme "Aqua" as a seven-day event, resulting in making a "Rollercoaster Tycoon-like" Aqueduct builder and manager game using a pixel-art top-down isometric art style.
- Planned a seven-day project lifecycle to develop a playable product within the time frame of the GameJam, resulting in an efficient creation and learning experience.

Indie-Game Developer, Bugs Tower Defense

July 2023 – March 2024

- Created a demo tower defense video game and published it on Itch.io to learn the full game development process from scratch to a playable, polished product.
- Play-tested the tower defense game extensively to minimize bugs and received feedback from friends and family to improve the overall gameplay experience and gamebalancing.

AWARDS & RECOGNITIONS

2022 - Published Research Paper on Novel Optimization Algorithm

2019 - University of Surrey Prestige Scholarship

2019 - ICHK Growth Mindset Scholarship B

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

- ∉ Game Development I make games as a hobby and always have a GameJam or indiegame project I'm working on.
- ∉ Touch Rugby Played competitively in Hong Kong leagues even facing off against a team captained by the French national team captain (former world number 1 team).